

 \times

akshayrodi@gmail.com



+91-8976306387



Kandivali West, Mumbai, India



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ak shay-rodi-02356392

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

Skills-

- Financial Analysis
- Auditing
- o Financial Reporting
- Taxation
- o Management Accounting
- Interpersonal Skills

<u>COMPUTER & ERP</u> <u>EFFICIENCY-</u>

- SAP
- Navision ERP
- o Oracle
- o Tally ERP & Tally Prime
- MS office (Word, Excel & Power point)
- Computax Online

Akshay J. Rodi

Chartered Accountant

A focused individual with four years+ post qualification experience in the field of Accounts, Audit & Assurance and Taxation. Seeking to leverage my skill set and zest for learning to secure a position which will be challenging, rewarding and which will provide opportunities for progression while contributing to the growth of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Executive – Audit & Assurance Services

M/s Mukund M Chitale & Co., Mumbai

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2024

[Renowned CA Firm in Mumbai with 11 partners having professional presence over 50 years.]

- Limited review, statutory audit and tax audit of construction, manufacturing and service sector. (listed/unlisted companies).
- Audit of consolidated financials of construction & service sector. (listed companies).
- Review of financial statements of companies in compliance with Ind AS, Indian GAAP and Schedule III of the Companies Act 2013.
- Conducted and performed Internal Financial Control testing for private companies covering areas such as HR, Fixed Assets, Procure to pay, Revenue, Borrowings & Financial statement closure.
- Obtained an understanding of various business processes, controls, and risk management systems through discussions with process owners and client teams.
- Demonstrated strong teamwork skills and consistently met deadlines effectively.

Tax & Audit Associate

S. N. Katdare & Co., Mumbai

Aug.2016 - Feb.2021

Article Assistant

S. N. Katdare & Co., Mumbai

Aug.2013 - Jul.2016

1. Taxation:

- Preparation and timely filing of Monthly GSTR1, GSTR3B and doing the payments.
- Preparation of GSTR2B reconciliation with books of accounts.
- GST Audit and Filing.
- Monthly TDS working and payments, quarterly TDS return filing.
- Income Tax Return Filing for Individuals, Firms, LLPs, Trusts & Companies.
- Preparation & filing of Tax Audit Report.
- MVAT & Service Tax return filing.
- Professional Tax Return & Assessment.
- LBT Working, Return & Assessment.

2.Audit:

- Conducted statutory and internal audits for companies in retail, service & construction industries
- Planned & executed review of financial statements and compliance with Ind AS, Indian GAAP and Schedule III of the Companies Act 2013.
- Drafting Audit Reports as per the new reporting requirements of Companies Audit Report Order, 2020.
- Physical verification of stock on quarterly as well as yearly basis.

3. Other Areas:

- Accounting and finalization of books of various entities.
- Drafting, preparation & submission of response to assessment orders for Income Tax and Indirect Tax notices.
- Determining Financials and Economic viability of the client through Cash Flows projection and prepare CMA reports to obtain credit facility from banks.

EDUCATION

Degree/ Standard	Board/ Institute	Month/Year of Passing	Percentage/ Grade
Chartered Accountant	Institute of Chartered Accountant of India	May 2019	54.13%
B. Com	Mumbai University	March 2014	C Grade
H.S.C.	Maharashtra Board	March 2014	78.50%
S.S.C.	Maharashtra Board	March 2009	84.76%

LANGUAGES

- ♦ English
- ♦ Hindi
- ♦ Marathi

PERSONAL ASSETS

Quick Learning, Humbleness, and Loyalty are my greatest assets.

DATE OF BIRTH

• 08th June 1993